Guide to the Charlie Ahearn hip-hop archive, 1977-2012.
Ahearn, Charlie hip-hop archive
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Charlie Ahearn hip-hop archive, 1977-2012.
8078
Ahearn, Charlie.
10 cubic feet.
Audio recordings, manuscripts, photographs, publications, video
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Collection includes film production records, flyers, posters, original art, videos, audio, oral histories, photographs, slides, and vinyl recordings documenting early hip hop culture and the film "Wild Style."
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Charlie Ahearn (born 1951) is a New York City film director and creative artist. Although mainly involved in film and video production, he is also known as an author and radio host. He wrote, directed, and produced the 1983 hip-hop film "Wild Style."
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Collection includes film production records, flyers, posters, original art, videos, audio, oral histories, photographs, slides, and vinyl recordings documenting early hip hop culture and the film "Wild Style."
SUBJECTS
Names:
Ahearn, Charlie.
Titles:
Wild style (Motion picture)
Subjects:
Hip-hop -- New York (State) -- New York.; Rap (Music) -- New York (State) -- New York.; Graffiti -- New York (State) -- New York.; Break dancing -- New York (State) -- New York.; Disc jockeys.
Places:
Bronx (New York, N.Y.)
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
By appointment only.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Wild Style Materials
Series II. Documents and Manuscripts
Series III. Published Material
Series IV. Ephemera
Series V. Artwork and Posters
Series VI. Photographs and Slides
Series VII. Audio Visual Materials
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Wild Style Materials
  - Wild Style images for book (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
  - Wild Style photographs (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Wild Style fliers, publicity materials, xerox images (Box 4, Folder 4-6)
  - Wardance Treatment and Hip Hop over Tokyo (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Wardance (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Distribution Independent Feature project (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Wild Style photographs and negatives (Box 4, Folder 9, 14)
  - Early script notes (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Storyboards (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Twins DAS Stuff etc. (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Notebook (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Original scripts (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Old Wild Style notes (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Shooting Scripts, extras, schedule (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Irene Fornes writing workshop (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Invoices (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Charlie Ahearn comedian (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Hip Hop over Tokyo (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Teal (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - The Black Door (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Wild Child notes, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Bad Luck in Chinatown (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Copies of articles, publicity (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Star Child (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Martial Arts Musical (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Art Kraft the Dance (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Photographs- Japan and Germany, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Wild Style in Germany (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Kell Futura Train and Wild Style Back (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Wild Style photographs (Box 5, Folder 4-6)
  - Wild Style clippings (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Old article xeroxes (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Xeroxes, clippings (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous old press materials (Box 5, Folder 11-13)
- Series II. Documents and Manuscripts
  - Crazy Legs paper, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Lakim Shabazz articles, interview, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Just Say No! rap, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Battle for World Supremacy articles (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - LA Star, Digital Underground (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Tribe Called Quest article and draft (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Last Poets material (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Rakim, Big Daddy Kane album articles (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - X-Clan interviews, materials (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Queen Latifah article papers (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Brand Nubian, King Sun materials (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Third Base articles (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Monie Love material (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Experience Music E-Book (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Orals used in EMP book (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Interview materials (Box 5, Folder 29-30)
  - Interviews (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - EMP Material (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Rocking: Gang culture and the beginning of hip-hop paper (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Ledgers (Box 6, Folder 4-5)
- Series III. Published Material
  - Marvel comics, 1970s-1980s (Box 6, Folder 7-8)
  - DC comics, 1970s-1980s (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous other comics (Box 6, Folder 10-11)
  - Miscellaneous magazines (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Series IV. Ephemera
  - Miscellaneous fliers and cards (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Articles and ephemera (Box 7)
  - Articles and ephemera (Box 8)
  - Wild Style hat, belt, and miscellany (Box 14)
- Series V. Artwork and Posters
  - Two framed pieces (Box 11)
  - Lee Quinones canvas city scape, painted on location. Wild style., 1981 (Box 12)
  - Fliers and miscellaneous (Box 13)
  - Fliers (Box 15)
  - Fliers and posters (Box 16)
  - Artwork (Box 17)
- Series VI. Photographs and slides
  - Photographs (Box 9-10)
  - Four slide carousels (Box 18)
  - Miscellaneous slides (Box 19)
  - Slides: Wild Style binder (Box 20)
  - Slides: Ahearn duplicates binder (Box 20)
  - Slides: Ahearn originals binder (Box 20)
  - Slides: Ahearn originals binder (Box 20)
  - Slides: Ahearn original graffiti binder (Box 20)
  - Slides: originals binder (Box 20)
  - Slides: Ahearn Original EMP scans binder (Box 20)
- Series VII. Audio visual materials
  - Celebrity Club #1, 1980; V-6041 (Box 1)
  - Celebrity Club #2, 1980; V-6042 (Box 1)
  - Celebrity Club #3, 1980; V-6043 (Box 1)
  - Celebrity Club #4, 1980; V-6044 (Box 1)
  - Celebrity Club #5, 1980; V-6045 (Box 1)
  - Celebrity Club #1, 1980; V-6046 (Box 1)
  - Celebrity Club #2, 1980; V-6047 (Box 1)
  - Celebrity Club #4, 1980; V-6048 (Box 1)
  - Celebrity Club DUB #2, V-6049 (Box 1)
  - Celebrity Club DUB #3, V-6050 (Box 1)
  - Celebrity Club edit, V-6051 (Box 1)
  - Wild Style ABC 20/20 rap, V-6052 (Box 1)
  - RAI TV, 1981; V-6053 (Box 1)
  - Master edit, V-6054 (Box 1)
  - Wild Style Trailer and Basketball, V-6055 (Box 1)
  - Wild Style music video, long version, V-6056 (Box 1)
  - Edit Master, V-6057 (Box 1)
  - New York City Hip Hop Convention, 1980; V-6058 (Box 2)
  - Camara Master Reel #1, Funky 4, December 20, 1980; V-6059 (Box 2)
  - Funky 4 Reel #2, December 20, 1980; V-6060 (Box 2)
  - Funky Four Reel #3, December 20, 1980; V-6061 (Box 2)
  - Funky 4 Reel #4, December 20, 1980; V-6062 (Box 2)
  - Funky 4 Reel #5, December 20, 1980; V-6063 (Box 2)
  - Celebrity Club DUB #4, V-6064 (Box 2)
  - Funky Four + 1 DUB #4, V-6065 (Box 2)
  - Funky Four + 1 DUB #5, V-6066 (Box 2)
  - Funky Four/Rink, December, 1980; V-6067 (Box 2)
  - Smith Gym "Uprocking Stuff", 1977; F-389 (Box 2)
  - Cassette tapes (Box 3)
  - Vinyl collection (Box 21)